

Ashish Gupta

Sustainability and Technology Expert

Passionate individual with over 20+ years of strong Leadership experience with creative out-of-box innovative thinking. Core Competence in Entrepreneurship, Sustainability (Agriculture), Resilience, Strategic systems thinking, Project management and implementation. Aiming to co-create wide scale systems for sustainability benefits (social, ecological and economic) based on Information Technology.

embed.ashishg@gmail.com

+91.9810348193

O Delhi, India

in linkedin.com/in/guptaji

github.com/embedashishg

SKILLS

Business Intelligence

Computer Networks Design

Device Driver Framework

Embedded Systems Design

Entrepreneurial Development

Growth Strategies

Market Placement and Marketing

Testing Infrastructure Design

Project Management

Root Cause Analysis and Mitigation

Systems Architecture

Enterprise Solutions

Strategic Leadership

Requirement Analysis

Training and Mentorship

Technology Integration

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Systems Architect

GISIL Designs - Indepay Networks

07/2007 – 07/2008 Systems Designs - POS Terminal Hardware, Embedded Systems for Fintech

Achievements/Tasks

Gurgaon, India

- Managed Systems Engineering Technical Leadership as Solutions Architect as single position for strategic alignment of devices for the Company Terminal - USB stack devices, Biometric Systems, Payment Card Device, Pin Entry Device (PED), PCI DSS Complaince
- Developed Solutions for Secure PoS terminals, PCI DSS Compliance for PED EMV Level 2 Kernel, Cryptography applications, Processor Virtualization for ARM7 and USIP Chipsets
- Successful Integration Solutions for Biometrics Stack, Bar code, Fingerprint enrollment, de-duplication check ISO 19794 compliance
 Developed High Level Enterprise Architecture systems for implementing Biometric inclusion of large population base
- Successfully executed root cause analysis for Enterprise system problems for financial inclusion and card payment systems based on lava FF

Senior Lead Software Engineering

Conexant Systems

06/2004 – 07/2007

Noida, India

Now Acquired by Synaptic Inc Achievements/Tasks

- Managed Technical Engineering team of 3-6 engineers for various projects by assigning technical tasks, code reviews, design documentation - High Level and Detailed, DevOps functions - Code merging, conflict resolution, build and deploy cycles within release timelines.
- Implemented New Design for Packet Classifier Using Boolean trees, AND-OR Graphs for team-wide IP DSLAM memory and cycles Optimization. Coding in C and Unit, Integration and Systems Testing using Shell scripts and custom code.
- Redesigned Packet Classification framework to reclaim over 2 MB of Embedded RAM and Flash space optimizing memory space. Coded DHCP (Static and Dynamic) Protocol Stack for IP discovery based on RFC Standard for IP DSLAM.
- Slashed timelag for control path filter configuration in Dataplane by over 100%. Successful Root Cause Analysis on issues related to timing of Large Scale Packet Classifier operations.
- Executed various roles for Data and Control Path development for IPSEC VPN, QOS, Firewall and Packet Classification for ADSL Modem, based on Embedded Linux. Root Cause Analysis for ADSL Kernel crashes patches and build stability.
- Created Architecture and High level design for a network processor to perform quick look-ups of inline packets based on propreitory hashing function and lookup hardware. Applied for Innovation Disclosure to Internal Company IPR department.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Various Organisations (NIKSUN India, Pixtel Communications, iPolicy Networks)

09/2000 - 06/2004

Pixtel Acquired by Mediatek, iPolicy Acquired by Tech Mahindra

Multiple Locations, India

Delhi, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Successfully Designed, Development, Debugging and Deployment of Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS), Firewall, Packet Filtering and Injection Frameworks in various teams of 2-3 engineers in multiple projects. Coded Projects in Java EE (Client-Server using Servlets) to Implement Smart packet detectors for IDS (NIKSUN India).
- First Coding Implementation of IPX packet filtering by modification of the Berkley Packet Filter (BPF) based on FreeBSD Kernel. . Part of Development team of 4 Engineers to reconstruct IP packet flows based on tracking RADIUS IP assignment for TCP reconstruction and offline packet search on a Non-Intrusive Pattern Matching Device (NIKSUN India).
- Developed interfaces for MMI, Call Management state machine and Protocol Stack Integration for ARM based GSM/GPRS Chipset with collaboration with Mediatek (Taiwan) Code Debugging using Trace32 ICD on board for release stability (Pixtel).
- Developed tools, software and testing framework for High speed packet filtering and matching on various Network security devices on Control Plane for High Speed Networks (NAT/Firewall) (iPolicy Networks).

Entrepreneur Roles

Organic Way of Life, Jaivik Haat Private Limited &

09/2008 – Present

Marketing and Supply Platform for Connecting Farmers to Consumers

Achievements/Tasks

- 100% Single Handed Successful Business Establishment from ground-up for over a decade. Successful Compliance and Crisis Management during COVID-19 lockdown for business continuity. 30% YoY increase in sales, based on strartegic partnerships, inventory, sourcing and marketing
- Achieved sales turnover of 40lacs+ from 3rd Year Onward with Negligible debt exposure. Break-even achieved 3rd Year Onwards
- Ensured Fair pricing to farmers and transparency to consumers Assisted additional farming initiatives in Entrepreneurship development - Various locations in India
- Successfully transitioned business through equity transfer to Non-Profit for continuity

Social Sustainability Brief - Consulting, Founding and Probono

Various Organisations (FAO, WHH, APO, IFOAM-OI, OFAI, PGSOC, GDT, DOFM) - Sustainable Agriculture

10/2010 – 07/2019 India

Food and Agriculture Organisation of United Nations (FAO), Welthungerhilfe (WHH), Asia Productivity Organisation (APO) etc Achievements/Tasks

- Advised FAO on Sustainable Food Systems Capacity Development, Sustainable Development Goals (SDG 2.4.1) Frameworks, Participatory Guarantee Systems (PGS), Big-Data Analytics for Smallholder farming clusters in India.
- Assisted APO with creation of Training Programs on Social Entrepreneurship for Rural Development for Government Employees and NGOS for 18 countries in Asia.
- Created Scalable Food Systems Platform for WHH for connecting 5 NGOS and over stakeholders 3000 farmers to localized markets.
- Served as First Vice President of IFOAM-Asia, a pan Asian body for promotion of Sustainable Agriculture in over 6 countries across Asia.
- Successfully Co-Founded Trusts (GDT and DOFM) as per Legal Compliances including designing suitable objectives, statues and functional programs on Market Platforms, Capacity Building for Small producers and family farmers, Mountain Sustainability.
- Served as Board member and contributed to organisation development, board meetings and advocacy for Sustainable Agriculture in Indias largest network Organic Farming Association of India (OFAI) and Secretary PGS Organic Council.

EDUCATION

Master of Science - Software SystemsBirla Institute of Technology and Sciences

06/2002 – 02/2005

9.10/10.0

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science And Engineering

Walchand Institute Of Technology (WIT)

06/1996 - 04/2004

First Class with Distinction

Page 2 of 3

IT TECHNICAL SKILLS

Computer Hardware

Enterprise

Systems

Security

Frameworks

Configuring and managing interfaces for ATM, Fibre, DSL. Ethernet 802.3, Cisco Routers, Switches, Packet/Crypto

Generators, JTAG, Lauterbach

Webservers, Cloud Computing (SaaS, PaaS, XaaS), Agile Methods (Scrum),

DevOps, SDLC, Test Automation, Versioning (Git, SVN), Machine Learning

IP VPN (PKIS, 3DES, IKE, MD5, SHA1), SSH, RSH, PKI, MD5, Firewalls, RADIUS, PCI PED. EMV Level 2. PKCS #1. Digital

Certificates.

Embedded Nucleus Plus, uCLinux, Integrity,

Systems Proprietary OS Computer Networks

OS

Kernels/Distros

TCP/IP - Stack Internals, Packet Shaping, Metering, Policing, Packet Drop Algorithms, Bridging protocols - L2,

VLAN, LLC, SNAP, L2 and L3 Multicast

Languages/Comp C/C++, GNU Tools, Java EE, Perl, GNU ilers/Interpreters linker, XML, TCL, Compilers (ARM, MIPS), /Tools

Assemblers (x86, ARM), Makefiles,

Lex/Yacc, Vim, Emacs, Tally

*BSD.Linux Kernel, Kernel Virtualization

(OLK4/Trango), Distro

(Ubuntu/Redhat/GNOME.KDE)

Standards RFC, ITU-T, POSIX, GSM ETSI Standards,

> 3GPP GSM Standards, IEEE, ISO 19794 Biometrics, EMV Level 2/2, PCI DSS

ORGANIZATIONS

Gram Disha Trust (09/2019 - Present)

Founding Trustee

Delhi Organic Farmers Market Trust (01/2019 - Present) 🗹

Founding Trustee

CERTIFICATES

Free Prior Informed Consent (FPIC) (12/2018 – Present)

Food and Agriculture Organisations (FAO) of the United Nations

Resilience in Food Security Analysis (11/2018 – Present)

Food and Agriculture Organisations (FAO) of the United Nations

INTERESTS

Backpacking and Travelling

Composting

Horticulture - Fruit Trees and Vegetables

Mountain Farming Systems

Mountaineering

Music - Guitar/Flute Play

SUPPORTED CAUSES

Ahinsa and Gandhism

Animal Welfare

Appropriate Technology for Agriculture

Crisis Relief

Food Safety and Nutrition

Sustainable Agriculture and Forestry

ACHIEVEMENTS

Post Graduate Thesis (06/2003 - 07/2004)

InterWeave - A Novel Network Processor Architecture for Active Networks. The thesis details requirements and challenges posed by Active networks. It proposes architecture of a network processor to support the requirements of such networks.

Research Paper Presentation - First Prize (1997)

Presented paper titled "Computer Simulation and Modeling" at National Level Presentation held at REC Kurukshetra and BITS Pilani. The paper elucidates various mathematical and empirical approaches to Computer Simulations and Modeling.

Research Paper Presentation - Quantum Computers (1998)

Presented paper titled "Ouantum Computers" at presentation by IEEE student's chapter held at Manipal Institute of Technology. A Primer to Quantum Computers, explains aspects of Communication and Cryptography and challenges in implementing the same.